{
  "questions": [ 
       {
           "question": "True or False: Java is a strongly typed language.",
           "answers": ["True", "False"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 1
       },
       {
           "question": "In Java Strings are primitive types.",
           "answers": ["True", "False"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 2
       },
       {
           "question": "Which of the following refers to creating an object using the keyword \"new\"?",
           "answers": ["assignment", "instantiation", "declaration", "iteration"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 2
       },
       {
           "question": "Which of the following is not a primitive type?",
           "answers": ["int", "char", "Float", "byte"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 3
       },
       {
           "question": "True or False: Java Strings are immutable.",
           "answers": ["True", "False"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 1
       },
       {
           "question": "What is variable declaration?",
           "answers": ["instantiating a class", "retrieving a return value from a method", "creating a primitive type variable", "stating a variable type and name"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 4
       },
       {
           "question": "What is the number 5 in this code: System.out.println(\"amount: \"+5);",
           "answers": ["a constant", "a variable", "a literal", "an object"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 3
       },
       {
           "question": "Which of the following primitive types can only have two possible values?",
           "answers": ["byte", "char", "boolean", "short"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 3
       },
       {
           "question": "Which of the following represents \"or\" in Java logic?",
           "answers": ["+=", "&&", "!", "||"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 4
       },
       {
           "question": "Which of the following ends an infinite for loop?",
           "answers": ["stop();", "end;", "break;", "exit();"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 3
       },
       {
           "question": "What will this conditional test return if the value of \"num\" is 0: if((num>1) || (num>=0 && num<10))",
           "answers": ["True", "False", "null", "zero"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 1
       },
       {
           "question": "When does an else statement execute?",
           "answers": ["when at least one preceding \"if\" or \"else if\" statement has returned false", 
           "when all preceding \"if\" and \"else if\" statements have returned true", 
           "always regardless of what previous statements have returned", 
           "when all preceding \"if\" and \"else if\" statements have returned false"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 4
       },
       {
           "question": "What are the additive operators (plus signs) doing here: i++;",
           "answers": ["assigning", "concatenating", "incrementing", "decrementing"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 3
       },
       {
           "question": "What does the \"%\" operator return in Java arithmetic?",
           "answers": ["percentage", "remainder", "product", "factor"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 2
       },
       {
           "question": "What must \"a\" be here: while(a)",
           "answers": ["a number greater than or equal to zero", "an object reference", 
           "an expression that returns a value of true or false", "a primitive type variable"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 3
       },
       {
           "question": "Which of the following always starts an infinite while loop?",
           "answers": ["while(true) ", "while(num<0)", "while(;;)", "while(count==0)"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 1
       },
       {
           "question": "How many times will the following for loop execute: for(int i=0; i<=10; i++) { System.out.println(i); }",
           "answers": ["10", "11", "1", "0"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 2
       },
       {
           "question": "Which of the following data types cannot be used as the expression in a switch statement?",
           "answers": ["char", "Integer", "short", "Object"],
       	   "correctAnswer": 4
       } 
     ]
 }
